When I was 15, I was gang-raped by seven
men at a party. The next four years were
absolute [__] chaos. Drugs, more
abuse, rehabs, [music] psych lockups.
The thing about trauma is we all process
it completely different. Some people run
from the fire, I charged straight back
into it. I spent years [music]
continuing the destruction that they had
started. Then my little baby girl
Teralyn was born. That little girl was
my wake-up call. I could spend the rest
of my life being a victim of what had
happened to me, or I could choose to
start being a survivor. So, I pulled up
my goddamn boots and I got to work. I
became strong, independent, spicy, and I
learned to love myself. Not just the
good parts, the broken parts, the ugly
parts, the scarred parts. I've got
self-harm scars all over my body. Most
of them I've tattooed up, but they're
all still there, and I love them. They
tell my story. I finally became the
woman I wanted my daughter to look up
to. Your trauma is not your fault. Your
healing timeline is your healing
timeline. There is no deadline. There is
no perfect path, but eventually there
comes a point where you have to ask
yourself a very, very hard question. Is
your unhealed trauma hurting the people
that you love? Because your children are
watching. Your children learn how to
handle fear the way that you handle
fear. They learn how to handle pain the
way you handle pain. They learn what
strength looks like by watching you.
[music] And at some point you have to
realize and take responsibility for
understanding that the healing is no
longer just about you. It becomes about
everyone whose life you touch. [music] I
didn't heal cuz I suddenly felt better,
cuz I wanted to, cuz shadow work's fun.
I healed because my daughter deserved
better. And honestly, so did [music] I.
So did you. So did your daughter.
It's time to stop surviving and start
living.